Guide to the Stefan Brecht Papers MSS.355
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VI: Sound recordings
  - Mabou Mines- "The Warrior Ant"- "The Territory of Art" Radio Series a production of MOCA. Side A: The Large Scale Projects: Claes Oldenburg adn Coosje Van Bruggen. Side B: The Warrior Ant, 1984; ID: 355.0028 (Box 27, Media ID: 355.0028)
  - Mabou Mines- A Prelude to Death in Venice (with Bill Raymond) by Lee Breuer recorded by Bennett Theissen, May 17, 1986; ID: 355.0029 (Box 27, Media ID: 355.0029)
  - Lee Breuer interview about "Shaggy Dog Animation"- Tape Two, May 23, 1978; ID: 355.0030 (Box 27, Media ID: 355.0030)
  - Lee Breuer interview about "Shaggy Dog Animation"- Tape One, May 23, 1978; ID: 355.0031 (Box 27, Media ID: 355.0031)
  - Mabou Mines- "The Shaggy Dog Animation" Tape One Side One: Act One, Side Two: Act Two- end of Act Two on beginning of tape two., May 27-28, 1978; ID: 355.0032 (Box 28, Media ID: 355.0032)
  - Mabou Mines- "The Shaggy Dog Animation" Tape Two: Side One: End of Act Two and Act Three, May 27-28, 1978; ID: 355.0033 (Box 28, Media ID: 355.0033)
  - Mabou Mines- Bob Telson and Lee Breuer unreleased collaborations 1979-2002 [commercial release Disc One], undated; ID: 355.0034 (Box 27, Media ID: 355.0034)
  - Mabou Mines- Bob Telson and Lee Breuer unreleased collaborations 1979-2002. Commercial release Disc Two., undated; ID: 355.0035 (Box 27, Media ID: 355.0035)
  - Interview- Joan MacIntosh about Performance Group beginnings fall in 1967 to Spring 1968, June 29, 1985; ID: 355.0036 (Box 27, Media ID: 355.0036)
  - Interview- Richard Schechner about Free Southern Theatre, Workshop preceeding Performance Group- Tape One, April 3, 1986; ID: 355.0037 (Box 27, Media ID: 355.0037)
  - Interview- Richard Schechner about Free Southern Theatre, Workshop preceeding Performance Group- Tape Two, April 3, 1986; ID: 355.0038 (Box 27, Media ID: 355.0038)
  - Interview- Joan MacIntosh about Performance Group 1967 and 1968, March 22, 1986; ID: 355.0039 (Box 27, Media ID: 355.0039)
  - Interview- Joan MacIntosh about Performance group beginnings Fall of 1967 through Spring of 1968, June 29, 1985; ID: 355.0040 (Box 27, Media ID: 355.0040)
  - Interview- Richard Schechner, March 12, 1986; ID: 355.0041 (Box 27, Media ID: 355.0041)
  - Richard Schechner- New York University Humanities Council: 2 of 2, March 19, 1991; ID: 355.0042 (Box 27, Media ID: 355.0042)
  - Richard Schechner- New York University Humanities Council: 1 of 2, March 19, 1991; ID: 355.0043 (Box 27, Media ID: 355.0043)
  - "Carmilla: A Vampire Tale"- The original cast recording of the off-broadway musical presented by The ETC Company of La Mama/ New York, 1972; ID: 355.0044 (Box 28, Media ID: 355.0044)
    Original format: 12" vinyl sound disc
- Series VII: Video recordings
  This series contains six videotapes. All titles should reflect where the videos were removed from, except for "Olga's House of Shame" which was separated from Series IV: Performance Group "Wooster Group"
  - Mabou Mines- "An Epidog" City Arts Performance, February 2, 1996; ID: 355.0045 (Box 28, Media ID: 355.0045)
    Original format: VHS
  - Stuart Sherman- "Berlin (West)/Andere Richtungen", undated; ID: 355.0046 (Box 28, Media ID: 355.0046)
  - Stuart Sherman- Four Videos: "Berlin (West)/Andere Richtungen" 1986, "Gray Matter" 1987, "Video Walk" 1987, "Five Flowers" 1980, undated; ID: 355.0047 (Box 28, Media ID: 355.0047)
  - "Olga's House of Shame" Something Weird Video, 1964; ID: 355.0048 (Box 28, Media ID: 355.0048)
  - Selections from "Stuart Sherman's Eleventh Spectacle (The Erotic)" and "Portrait of Stuart Sherman" from The Eighth Spectacle, undated; ID: 355.0049 (Box 28, Media ID: 355.0049)
    Original format: 3/4" Umatic
  - Mel Andringa- His work at University of Iowa City, 1977 Fall and Winter, January 4, 1978; ID: 355.0050 (Box 28, Media ID: 355.0050)
    Original format: 1/2" open reel video
- Series VIII: Films
  This series contains four films, all separated from Series II: Stuart Sherman.
  - Tree Film, undated; ID: 355.0051 (Reel 355.0051)
    Silent
    Original format: 16mm film, 24 fps
  - Skating, undated; ID: 355.0052 (Reel 355.0052)
  - Scotty and Stuart, undated; ID: 355.0053 (Reel 355.0053)
  - Edwin, undated; ID: 355.0054 (Reel 355.0054)
- Oversize Series I: Performance Overview Subject Files A-Z
  - Overview- En Garde Arts Presents, Film Forum, BAM, Art Services, [undated] (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Overview- [Living Theater, Festival D'Automne a Paris, Mel Andringa, Spalding Gray], [undated] (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Overview- 'Festivals of Alienation and Community' by James Leverett, Soho Weekly News, October 5, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Overview- The Village Voice Art Supplement vol. III, no. 1 [Andy Warhol], May 5, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Andringa, Mel- "Sistine Floor Plan" and "American Nervousness", [undated] (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Andringa, Mel- The Drawing Legion, December, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Andringa, Mel- Arts over AIDS- [with untitled Daily News, original artwork], 1985, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Andringa, Mel- The Memory Theatre of Giulio Camilla Thesis Submitted, May, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Andringa, Mel- "The Confidence Man", April, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Andringa, Mel- "Camillo" Hancher Circle News, vol. IV, no. 4, Winter, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Bark, Jared- 'Afterimage', April, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Brakhage, Stan- Whitney Museum 'The New American FIlmmakers Series', [undated] (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Chong, Ping- "Nuit Blanche", "Arace", February-March, 1984; [undated] (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Chong, Ping- "A.M./A.M.", "Fear and Loathing in Gotham", "Arace", "Nuit Blanche", February, 1985; [undated] (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Chong, Ping- "Kindness" [poster], [undated] (Folder 5)
  - Creation [Production Company]- La Mama Presents [April-June Calendar], [undated] (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Duo Theater- Spanish Theater "Rasputin", [undated] (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Evans, Joan- 'The Egg Session', [undated] (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Finley, Karen- Lincoln Center for Performing Arts, July-August, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Gehr, Ernie- Survival Research Laboratories and Millenium Personal Cinema Program, Spring, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Gehr, Ernie- Millennium Film Workshop, Fall, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Gibson, Jon- "Four Concerts", 1975; 1977 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Grooms, Red- "The Ruckus World of Red Grooms" Rutgers University Art Gallery, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Hatanaka, Minoru- "Spiral Complex", [undated] (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Jesurun,John- La Mama Presents February-March Calendar, [undated] (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Jones, Leroi (Amiri Baraka)- [Jarvis Tyner handout], August 14, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Living Theatre- "Downtown" Issue No. 96 [Julian Beck], May 11, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Living Theatre- "Exquisite Corpse" vol. 4; "Seven Meditations on Political Sado-Masochism", November-December, 1986; [undated] (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Living Theatre- "Open Road" [Interview with Judith Malina and Julian Beck], Spring, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - McLaughlin, Sheila- "She must be seeing things" [and program with Nancy Miller], Spring, 1978, [undated] (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Meat Productions- "Titus Andronicus", [undated] (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Pietri, Pedro- "Pre-Resurrection Insurrection", [undated] (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Reich, Steve- and Jon Gibson at the Kitchen, [undated] (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Saratoga International Theater Institute- Anne Bogart/Tadashi Suzuki, May-June, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Serban, Andrei- "Fragments of a Trilogy", 1973-1974 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - S.F. Mime Troupe- "False Promises/Nos Enganaron", December 15, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - Talkin Band- "Worksong", "Piedro Palermo", [undated] (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Whitman, Robert- "Raincover", "A Walk in the Park", October, 1982; September, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Whitman, Robert- "Prune Flat" and "Light Touch" at Dia Art Foundation, December, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 30)
  - Wilson, Ann- "Electric Affinity" and "Faust", 1976; [undated] (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - Wilson, Ann- Electric Affinity [with Jared Bark, "The Bird and The Dirt" at Institute of Contemporary Art, University of Pennsylvania], February-January, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - Young, La Monte, September-October, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Zorn, John- "EAR Magazine of New Music" vol. 2, no. 2, October, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 33)
  - Zorn, John- "Jai Alai", "Track and Field" [Collective for Living Cinema], Spring, 1982; [undated] (Box 30, Folder 34)
- Oversize Series II: Stuart Sherman
  - 8th Spectacle- Open Space and Playwrights Group Festival [poster], March, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 35)
  - 2nd Trilogy 'Strindberg, Brecht, and Chekov' at the Kitchen [poster], May-June, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 36)
  - Festival D'automne a Paris- 10th and 11th Spectacle and Short Films [Program], September-December, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 37)
  - 10th Spectacle (Portraits of Places)- The Museum of Modern Art Summergarden, [1978] (Box 30, Folder 38)
  - Filmworks- [posters], [undated] (Box 30, Folder 39)
  - Faust- Theater am Turm [German language poster], February, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 40)
  - "Hamlet" and "Faust"- [posters], [undated] (Folder 7)
  - Life Magazine- vol. 3 no.1, January, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 41)
- Oversize Series III: Mabou Mines
  - "Animal Magnetism"- Mabou Mines thirtieth anniversary, March, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Alternative Theatre vol. 1, no. 3- "From Becket to Breuer", January-February, 1975-1976 (Box 30, Folder 42)
  - The Village Voice vol. XXXII, no. 20- "Lee Breuer: American Theater's Wild Man", May 19, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 43)
  - The A.R.T. News vol. 6 no.2- "The Balcony" Joanne Akalaitis, January, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 44)
  - Zone no. 8- "Wrong Guys", Fall-Winter, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 45)
  - "The Photographer"- Next Wave BAM, Fall, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 46)
  - International Festival of Pupper Theater- La Mama E.T.C., September 10-22, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 47)
  - Next Wave Festival- [poster], [undated] (Folder 6)
- Oversize Series IV: Performance Group "Wooster Group"
  - L.S.D. Manifesto (2)- The Performing Garage, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Living Theatre- "Seven Meditations on Political Sado-Masochism" [Julian Beck and Judith Malina], April 5-13, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Richard Schechner- "Dionysis in 69" [New York University presents], March 19, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - The Wooster Group- "The Road to Immortality", "LSD", 1986-1987 (Box 30, Folder 48)
  - The Wooster Group- "Nyatt School", 1982 (Box 30, Folder 49)
  - Performance Group- "3 Places in Rhode Island" and "Childrens Theater Workshop", February, 1979; [undated] (Box 30, Folder 50)
  - Richard Schechner- "Mother Courage" [posters], Alternative Theater vol. 1 no.2- "Shamanism: A Swift Fly-Over", December, 1975; [undated] (Box 30, Folder 51)
  - Richard Schechner- Prometheus: Sexy New York The Guide, December-January, 1985-1986 (Box 30, Folder 52)
  - The Wooster Group- "Point Judith" Zone no. 7, Spring-Summer, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 53)
  - The North Carolina ANVIL vol. 6 no. 307 [article about The Living Theater with letter from Elizabeth LaCompte], April, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 54)
  - The Wooster Group- Spalding Gray and William DeFoe [articles from The New York Times and Interview], May, 1992; January 1993 (Box 30, Folder 55)
  - The Living Theater- xeroxes of Fred McDarrah photographs, [undated] (Box 30, Folder 56)
  - The Living Theater- Beverly Grant and The Human Condition and Steve Ben Israel, [undated] (Box 30, Folder 57)
  - "To You, The Birdie" (Phedre) [with Naropa poster], [undated] (Folder 8)
- Oversize Series V: Dance, Black Theatre, Black Music
  - Meredith Monk- "Education of the Girl Child", "Acts from Under and Above", "Specimen Days", April 22, 1986; December 2, 1981; [undated] (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Merce Cunningham Dance Company- Minskoff Theatre, January 18-22, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Yvonne Rainer- "Five Dance Performances" Anderson Theater, [undated] (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Yvonne Rainer- "Film about a woman who..." New American Filmmakers Series [poster], [undated] (Box 30, Folder 58)
  - Black Music- SQUAT Presents Sun Ra [plus Dorathy Donegan], [undated] (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Black Music- Olatunji Center of African Culture featuring Art Blakey,Jackie McClean, Lee Morgan, and McCoy Tyner, [undated] (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Black Music- Beaver Harris- New Music Distribution Service [interview], [undated] (Box 30, Folder 59)